vugg.net 2012-05-07

# SPAM

**Updated January 17, 2011**

Welcome. At Hormel Foods, your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy explains how Hormel Foods (“we, “ “us,” and “our”) protect your privacy when you visit our websites (our "Site(s)"). This Privacy Policy describes what types of information we gather and track when you use our Sites, how this information is used and with whom it is shared. 

**Scope of This Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy covers the "Personal Information" we collect through our Sites. "Personal Information" is information that identifies you personally, either alone or in combination with other information available to us. Examples of Personal Information include your name, address, email address, credit card information, image and the information you provide when you use one of our Sites to create an account or a personal profile. 

**Your Consent**

Please take a few minutes to review this Privacy Policy. By accessing or using one of our Sites you are consenting to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

IF YOU DO NOT CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AS SET FORTH IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE EXIT AND DO NOT USE THIS SITE. 

**What Personal Information Do We Collect Through Our Sites**

_Information You Provide_. We collect the Personal Information you knowingly provide (using your mouse and keyboard, cellular or mobile phones) when you use our Sites. The information we collect depends on how you use our Sites. For example, if you sign up to receive email communications from us, we collect your email address and any related information you provide. If you communicate with us using the "Contact Us" feature, we collect the information you provide when you complete the "Contact Us" form.

_Credit Card Information_. If you make a purchase on our Sites, Hormel Foods will collect and verify your credit card information. When you provide credit card information through our other Sites, the information you provide goes directly from your computer to a server operated by one of our service providers. The service provider uses your credit card information only to process your transaction and is bound by contract to treat all of your Personal Information as confidential. Although our service providers send us most of the information you provide when you complete a transaction (so that we know, for example, who has purchased a product and where to ship it), for your security, our service providers do not share your credit card information with us.

_Supplemental Information_. From time to time, we may supplement the information you give us with information from other sources, such as information validating your address or information based on your zip code. We may also supplement the information you give us with information we collect from you through other Hormel Foods Sites or other channels.

_Information Sent to Us by Your Web Browser_. We collect information that is sent to us automatically by your Web browser. This information typically includes the IP address of your internet service provider, the name and version of your operating system, the name and version of your browser, the date and time of your visit, and the pages you visit. Please check your browser if you want to learn what information your browser sends or how to change your settings. This information does not identify you personally. Generally, we use this information to improve our Sites and make them more compatible with the technology used by our visitors. In most cases, we do not link the information sent by your browser to information that identifies you personally. We do, however, review our server logs – which contain visitors' IP addresses -- for security purposes, such as detecting intrusions into our network. If we suspect criminal activity, we may share our server logs with the appropriate investigative authorities who could use that information to trace and identify individuals.

**How We Use Personal Information**

Generally. We use the Personal Information we collect through our Sites:  
to provide the products, information and services you request;  
for security, credit or fraud prevention purposes;  
to provide you with effective customer service;  
to provide you with a personalized experience when you use our Sites;  
to contact you with special offers and other information we believe will be of interest to you (but only with your permission);  
to contact you with information and notices related to your use of our Sites;  
to invite you to participate in surveys and provide feedback to us;  
to better understand your needs and interests;  
to improve the content, functionality and usability of our Sites; and  
to improve our products and services.

**Agreements Governing Your Use of Special Features**

Some of our Sites include special features and password-protected areas. For example, you may be able to use our Sites to apply for a job, to share recipes, or to design and email a "gram" to a friend, and send and receive text messages.

When you sign up to use a special feature or password-protected area, you may be asked to agree to special terms governing your use of the special feature or password-protected area. In such cases, you will be asked to expressly consent to the special terms, for example, by checking a box or clicking on a button marked "I agree." This type of agreement is known as a "click-through" agreement. If any of the terms of the click-through agreement are different than the terms of this Privacy Policy, the terms of the click-through agreement will supplement or amend this Privacy Policy, but only with respect to the matters governed by the "click-through agreement."

_"Email a Friend" Features_. Some of our Sites include "Email a Friend" features that allow you to forward information or customized communications to your friends. When you use one of these features, we will ask you to provide your friend's name and email address. We use this information only to customize and deliver your message. We do not add your friend's name or email address to our mailing lists. Some of our Email a Friend features permit you to upload photographs to customize your communication. We use the photographs you upload only to customize your communication. We do not use your photographs for any other purpose. 

**Password Protected Areas of This Site**

For your protection, certain areas of our Sites are password protected. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your passwords. We have the right to assume that anyone accessing our Sites using a password assigned to you has the right to do so. You will be solely responsible for the activities of anyone accessing our Sites using a password assigned to you, even if the individual is not, in fact authorized by you. If you have reason to believe that your password has been compromised or used without authorization, you must promptly change it using the functionality provided on the Site.

**How Does Hormel Foods Share My Personal Information**

_Service Providers_. We share Personal Information with companies and organizations that perform services on our behalf, for example, companies that provide support services to us (such as credit card processing services, data storage services, and web hosting services) or that help us market our products and services.

**Within Hormel Foods. We may share your Personal Information within Hormel Foods.**

_Business Transfers_. Your Personal Information may be transferred to a company that has acquired the stock or assets of Hormel Foods or one of our businesses, for example, as the result of a sale, merger, reorganization or liquidation. If such a transfer occurs, the acquiring company's use of your Personal Information will still be subject to this Privacy Policy and the privacy preferences you have expressed to us.

_Compliance With Laws and Protection of Our Rights and the Rights of Others_. We may disclose Personal Information when we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law, a court order or a subpoena. We may also disclose Personal Information to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to enforce or apply our online Terms of Use or other agreements; or to protect our own rights or property or the rights, property or safety of our users or others.

**Your Choices**

In General

We respect your right to make choices about the ways we collect, use and disclose your Personal Information. In most cases, we will ask you to indicate your choices at the time we collect your Personal Information. We will also include an "opt-out" link in newsletter or promotional email we send you so that you can inform us that you do not wish to receive such communications from us in the future. If you have created an account or a personal profile on one of our Sites, you may be able to update some or all of your privacy choices by changing the settings on your account settings or profile page.

**Direct Marketing**

Before we use your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes (or permit our affiliates to do so), we will offer you the opportunity to choose whether to have your information used in this way. If at any time you wish to be taken off our direct marketing mailing lists, please send us an email at [cresponse@hormel.com](mailto:cresponse@hormel.com) or write to us at Hormel Foods Corporation, Consumer Response, 1 Hormel Place, Austin, MN 55912 Please provide your full name, address and email address so that we can find you on our mailing lists. Once we have the information we need, we will remove you from our mailing lists. Please give us a reasonable amount of time to honor your request. 

**How Does Hormel Foods Protect Personal Information**

We take reasonable precautions to provide a level of security appropriate to the sensitivity of the Personal Information we collect. Although we use reasonable measures to help protect your Personal Information against unauthorized use or disclosure, we cannot guarantee the security of information provided over the internet or stored in our databases. 

**Links to Other Hormel Foods websites**

Hormel Foods operates many different websites, each with its own content, features, and functionality. Each Hormel Foods website serves a different purpose. For this reason, not all of our websites are governed by this Privacy Policy. When you use a link on one of our Sites to access another Hormel Foods website, please take a minute to review the privacy policy posted on that website. For a list of the Sites that are governed by this Privacy Policy, click here <http://www.hormelfoods.com/familyofsites.aspx>.

**Links to Third-Party websites**

This Site may also contain links to websites operated by other companies, including websites operated by our third-party service providers, our affiliates, and other third parties. This Privacy Policy does not apply to Personal Information collected on any of these third-party websites. When you access third-party websites through a link on this Site, please take a few minutes to review the privacy policy posted on that site. 

**Use of Cookies, Web Beacons and Similar Technologies by Third Parties**

_Marketing Consultants_. Our marketing consultants may use Web beacons, cookies and other Web technologies to collect information about visitors to our Sites. For example, our consultants may count how many visitors access our Sites, what links they use, and what pages they view. They may also track which websites and advertisements refer traffic to our Sites and the URLs of the sites to which our Sites refer traffic (that is, the websites on which our visitors land when they leave our Sites). Our consultants use this information to compile statistics and prepare reports that provide the feedback and analysis we need to understand the needs and interests of our visitors, improve the content, functionality and usability of our Sites, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising and marketing efforts. The information our consultants collect does not identify you personally.

If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. You may also delete our cookies as soon as you leave a Site. Although you are not required to accept our cookies when you visit our Sites, if you set your browser to reject cookies, you will not be able to use all of the features and functionality of our Sites.

_Advertising Companies_. We use third-party advertising companies to manage our online advertising campaigns. Our advertising companies use cookies and other Web technologies to target and measure the effectiveness of our advertisements. For example, our advertising companies place Web beacons on their clients' websites, including our Sites. When you visit these websites, the Web beacon "tags" your computer with a "cookie." The information stored on the cookie does not identify you personally and is not combined with any information that identifies you personally, but it does permit our advertising companies to recognize your computer when you access one of their clients' sites. Our advertising companies use the information they collect about your use of their clients' websites to customize the advertisements you see when you visit their clients' sites. Our advertising companies' use of cookies and other web technologies is covered by their privacy policies, not by this Online Privacy Statement. If you do not wish to receive our advertising companies' cookies, you may "opt-out" by following the directions in our advertising companies' privacy policies. For more information, click here - Web Trends Privacy Policy: [http://www.webtrends.com/AboutWebTrends/ PrivacyPolicy.aspx?promo=TI_silopriv_FT&WT.svl=ftr_privacy](http://www.webtrends.com/AboutWebTrends/%20PrivacyPolicy.aspx?promo=TI_silopriv_FT&WT.svl=ftr_privacy). 

**Children**

This Site is not directed to children and we will not request any information from children under 13. Hormel Foods does have other websites that are geared in whole or in party to a child audience. The privacy of children is described more fully in the privacy policies of those websites. We also recommend that parents monitor their children’s internet activities and employ software or other tools which can help their children access the internet without compromising their safety.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

As we add new features and functionality to our Sites, we may need to update or revise this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to do so, at any time and without prior notice, by posting the revised version on our Sites. Your use of one of our Sites following any such change constitutes your consent to the terms of the revised Privacy Policy. For this reason, it is important to review this Privacy Policy regularly. If we modify this Privacy Policy, we will provide a notice at the top of this Privacy Policy for at least 30 days after the new effective date. 

**Special Notice for Visitors Who Reside Outside the United States**

Hormel Foods is a U.S. corporation. Hormel Foods and its affiliates do business in more than 40 countries. Our headquarters are in Austin, Minnesota in the United States of America. Our Web servers and databases are located in the United States or in other countries. We may transfer your Personal Information to our service providers and others located in the United States or other countries for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Different countries have different privacy laws and requirements, and some, including the United States, provide less legal protection for your Personal Information than others. Please know, however, that no matter where your Personal Information is collected, used, transferred or stored, if it was collected through our Sites, it will be protected by the terms of this Privacy Policy and any privacy notices or click-through agreements that apply to you.

BY USING THIS SITE, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE COLLECTION, USE, AND TRANSFER OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN OR TO THE UNITED STATES OR ANY OTHER COUNTRY IN THE WORLD. 

**Governing Law**

This Privacy Policy is governed under the laws of the State of Minnesota, United States of America without regard to its conflicts of law provisions. 

**Questions Concerning Our Privacy Practices**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices:

Send an e-mail to [cresponse@hormel.com](mailto:cresponse@hormel.com) and write "Privacy" in the subject line

Write to us at  
Hormel Foods Corporation  
1 Hormel Place  
Austin, MN 55912-3680  
Attn: Legal Dept.
